Hey everybody, welcome back to the three
questions series from the Alliance. I am
here today with our own
Casey Cockrum.
Casey's going to answer our questions
first, but first, tell me who you are. I
know who you are. Tell me how you're
related to the Alliance. Why do I
already know you?
I currently serve on the advisory board
for the Alliance. That's exactly right.
I've loved
That's exactly right. We sucked her in
and we got her to stay. I would love to
ask our normal three questions. I have
known Casey for a while.
Loved her for a long time.
So tell everybody who's listening,
what's your little corner of the
kingdom? Tell us that first. Where do
you work? Who are your people? What are
you doing?
Yeah, so I live in Memphis, but I work
for RUF, Reformed University Fellowship.
And I serve as the assistant vice
president of the campus staff
department. That's a long word, long
title. But essentially, I help along
with a couple of other people do the
care, hiring, developing the campus
staff department within RUF.
And what's the campus staff department?
Yeah, so campus staff is a It's a job
descript- This I'll try to give you the
job description. What we're trying to do
is hire women who want to serve long
term on a college campus. So one of the
most beautiful things about RUF is that
we have ordained campus ministers. We
hire men who have been to seminary.
They're ordained in the Presbyterian
Church in America. And then another
title that's known pretty well in RUF is
the internship, and that's a two to
three-year commitment.
And then we've had some campus staff
over the years. I was one in the early
2000s, but in 2015 is what I really
started to develop the department. And
it is a position for women who want to
serve post-RUF internship. So they may
do the internship and get a seminary
degree while they're working for RUF as
a campus staff, or they may go away to
seminary and then come back and work for
us.
It's a three to five-year commitment.
Our retention has actually been longer
than that. We've We've averaged around
seven or eight years of women staying.
Wow.
>> the beautiful thing about about this job
is that they serve under the leadership
of that ordained campus minister, but
serve as co-laborers. Mhm.
>> just, you know, with with the college
campus having more women than men, it's
a really
really needed position. Right.
It's wonderful. Okay, so I would love to
hear I would love to hear like five
stories, but we have time for one story
of how God has used this ministry
recently or how you've seen him use you.
Okay.
Let's Let's talk about them more than
anything else.
One of my favorite This is one of my
favorite stories. So campus staff can
serve on a co-ed school under the campus
minister, or they have the opportunity
at an all-female school to serve as a
director. Mhm. So they're in charge of
the ministry and they're in charge of
the women who are in that school.
We have a campus staff right now at
Wellesley in Boston.
And Catherine Perkins is her name, and
she worked She was an undergrad at
Harvard, went to Gordon-Conwell to
seminary, came back to Harvard and
worked for a while. But she had a
10-year prayer dream where she prayed
for 10 years straight, and she did and a
few of us did, for her to be able to
come to Wellesley and start RUF there.
Which by the way, for those who don't
know, Wellesley is an all- female
>> All-female school. Yeah, Hillary Clinton
went to that school. There's some other
It's a prominent school.
And she Yeah, spent 10 years praying for
this, and she started the ministry. And
so when she started the ministry, I went
to go and do a campus visit, and we
walked the campus. She's like, is this
going to work? And I was like, it's it's
already working. You're here. Mhm. And
we We So we walked the campus, and she
said I was like, "What's the prayer?"
And she said, "Let's start praying for
10 10 women to come." I was like, great,
10 women. So we prayed for weeks for 10
women to come. And about six weeks into
campus starting, she sent me a picture
with herself and 10 women in a Bible
study.
>> [laughter]
>> And you just think, what?
I mean, that's like a
It's such a beautiful picture to to me
to see these really
incredibly gifted women women using
their gifts and
>> Yeah. And then all across the country
these women are are are meeting with
students and girls are coming to know
Jesus and being baptized and they're
joining churches. Mhm.
>> It's not Our Our purpose in RUF is not
to just get reach people on the campus.
We want to reach them, equip them, and
send them to the church.
>> Mhm. And they're joining churches as
college students. It's beautiful. So
beautiful.
>> Which is not the norm, I would guess,
among most missions of college.
Definitely not. Ugh.
It's very encouraging. I would love to
If we had more time, I would love to
line them up like a bunch of campus
staff and just let them tell stories
like that, cuz I know they have stories
like that. So
>> in the future. Maybe we can do a longer.
So
So if we, we meaning your brothers and
sisters out here in the PCA,
could support you in some way in what
you do and support campus staff and what
they do, what would it be? Like what
would be your ask of us?
Yeah, I've been thinking about that
since you sent me the questions. I I
You know, I think one of the things is
if you had If you were at a place that
has RUF and you have a campus staff,
a quick note or coffee or anything, male
or female,
if you're a pastor or if you're a lay
member of the church, just to reach out
to these women, encourage them with a
phone call or a text and just say, "I
see you." Mhm. And so
ministry's hard for men and women. It's
not just hard for women. Um but our
women really
they desire to be doing this ministry,
and fundraising is probably their
hardest thing is to get the funds raised
because the position is still so new.
They're used to the internship. Okay, we
get you for two years, or campus
minister, they're there long term
running the ministry. What is this role?
How is it fit?
And it's still so new even 11 years in.
So I think just having our campus staff
be seen, maybe financially supported,
that would be extra an extra good gift.
But I would say if you get to know them,
you will be so blessed and encouraged. I
mean, I really I have the greatest job
in the PCA and I have the greatest job
in the world. I really do. I get to deal
with these And I have people tell me
that all the time. Like, I know. Yeah.
>> say, "I want your job." And I was like,
"No no no, do not kick me out of this
job."
>> Yes. Um
>> [clears throat]
>> I really think if you could know any of
you could know them, you would be just
way more encouraged and blessed.
I would totally agree. I had I've had I
think just one as a student. Yeah. And
she's just Well, they're still
Yeah.
>> They're just gold. Yeah. Thank you,
Casey, for your work and for being
willing to just tell more people about
what's going on. I appreciate you. I
appreciate you.